## Ioni Solarz

In my years in the industry I've been involved in a variety of software companies as a developer focusing in sharpening my skills. I'm a Passionate software practitioner involved in variety of languages and frameworks with several years of experience and responsibility.

I'm always eager to confront new technologies and surpass myself. I want to keep learning and growing as a software developer, working in challenging endeavors and using all my experience to improve the product and the team.

**Specialties**: Software architecture, PHP, ASP.NET (WebForms, MVC), Web application "Front end" technologies (HTML, JS & CSS), ORM frameworks, Agile technologies, client support, remote collaboration, offshoring and interdisciplinary projects

## **Experience**

#### R/GA - Senior software engineer

2011- Present

Design, development and maintenance of web applications and backend services using PHP, MySQL, .NET stack and MS SQL Server. Design and implementation of a highly scalable DB and Server infrastructure using Azure.

Clients I worked for: PwC, Microsoft, McCormick, Verizon

#### **Baufest** - Lead Developer

2010 - 2011

Design, development and maintenance of web applications and backend services using .NET Tech Stack and MS SQL Server. Documentation and designing architecture solutions and frameworks.

### Tecnosoftware - Senior Developer

2008 - 2010

Design, development and maintenance of web and desktop applications and backend services using .NET Tech Stack (Asp.Net Mvc, WCF, WPF, EF, etc) and associate third party products such as MS SQL Server

Documentation and designing architecture solutions and frameworks

## Quadratica - Developer

2006 - 2008

My tasks consisted in the analysis, design and development (coding, testing, etc.) in the projects in which I participated. The projects were on the .Net technologies, and PHP, using MSSQL Server, MySQL and PostgreSQL.

Some of the technologies I worked with: DRM, digital media content protection. Sending of SMS via a custom made system. Net 1.1 and Asp.NET. Using Visual Studio Tool for Office to develop an application with Excel as front-end.

#### Cabinet of Ministers - Developer

2006 - 2006

Development and customization of the e-learning platform Moodle for the State Modernization Project by the Cabinet of Ministers

## Universidad de Flores -Developer

2001 - 2006

# Ioni Solarz

Design, development and maintenance of the internal applications, developed in Perl with Postgresql on Linux servers

In my time there I developed a new student management system for the administration department (billing system) using the above tools. I also developed a system for courses registration, exams and academic queries accessible through the university site.

#### Virtual Consulting - Web Developer

2003 - 2004

I developed web sites in php with mysql (using javascript and css) and was in charge of the maintenance of previously developed sites for the company. Some of the sites involved in the development were:

- www.fleni.org.ar
- www.bellamar.com.ar
- www.pablomassey.com
- www.malba.com.ar

## **Education**

Universidad de Palermo

2006 - 2011

**BS, Computer Science** 

Instituto Terciario O.R.T

2000 - 2004

**Computer System Analyst, Information Technology** 

## Languages

- Spanish
- English
- Hebrew